TIMOTHY GILMORE

Bloomington, IN · 603-417-8858 · timgilm.pages.iu.edu/portfolio/home.html

Results-oriented professional offering strong knowledge of testing, software development and engineering practices with experience in ITAR, manufacturing, and laboratory environments. Problem solver with demonstrated excellence in leadership and technical environments.

EDUCATION

2023 - PRESENT:

BS COMPUTER SCIENCE, INDIANA UNIVERSITY – BLOOMINGTON

PROFICIENCIES

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES:

- C
- Java
- Python
- HTML5
- CSS

TECHNOLOGIES:

- SFTP
- Unix
- EMACS
- Microsoft Office
- Windows

EXPERIENCE

8/2023 - CURRENT

UNDERGRADUATE INSTRUCTOR, LUDDY SCHOOL OF INFORMATICS, COMPUTING, AND ENGINEERING (INDIANA UNIVERSITY)

- Grade homework, assignments, and exams.
- Formulate individualized feedback for students that provides them with insight into what they can improve.
- Schedule, facilitate, and host office hours to answer questions from students and provide support.
- Provide lectures on topics that most students find challenging while encouraging active participation and feedback.
- Facilitate labs for approximately 20 students.

10/2020 - 9/2022

ELECTRICAL OPTICAL ASSEMBLER II, OPTICS 1

- Align developmental class 4 laser systems to a high standard using various methods of data collection and optical equipment.
- Analyze test results, technical specifications, and laser characteristics to troubleshoot root cause of failures.
- Inspect failed electronics and their individual components for damage and rework when possible.
- Collect and present information to triage issues for the engineering team to address.
- Assist engineers in extensive tests to qualify products to transition them from development to production.
- Work independently and efficiently to accomplish tasks in a timely manner.
- Follow written work instructions and verbal expectations.

06/2020 - 10/2020

MATERIAL HANDLER (TEMP POSITION), COLT REFINING

- Test electronic equipment and analyze results to resolve failures.
- Use Unix skills to operate industrial networking technology.
- Inspect electronics and their components for both physical and cosmetic damage.
- Utilize online and physical documents and resources to gain depth of understanding on the equipment and its operation.
- Capitalize on critical thinking skills to independently resolve a variety of technical problems.

07/2018 - 06/2020

RESTAURANT MANAGER, PAPA GINO'S

- Managed a diverse team of up to 25 direct reports using effective communication and collaborative teamwork while ensuring an elevated level of customer satisfaction.
- Performed personnel development tasks including interviewing for hourly positions, conflict resolutions, training, and performance evaluations.
- Performed vital operation management tasks such as financial accounting, inventory management, sales forecasting, scheduling, and vendor ordering.
- Ensured all operations follow company procedures and protocols.

SKILLS

- Leadership
- Teaching
- Software troubleshooting
- Hardware troubleshooting
- Network equipment troubleshooting
- Self-directed worker
- Critical thinking
- Problem solving

- Conflict resolution skills
- Excellent communication skills
- Time management
- Attention to detail
- Solution oriented
- Root cause analysis
- Technical
- Efficient

ACTIVITIES

01/2022-06/2022

CHAIRPERSON, Morale Activities and Culture Team (Optics 1)

- Find ways to go beyond the expectations to express appreciation for employees, their families, and the community.
- Strategize ways to keep employees motivated and excited about their work environment.
- Manage an annual budget.
- Present quarterly status of current and upcoming initiatives in company-wide meetings.
- Delegate responsibilities and tasks to members.
- Help in hosting annual events for employees and their families to attend.
- Uphold and reinforce the company's core values.